Kamrul Hasan

Experienced Full Stack Web Developer

01831-624571

@ kallol.business.ds@gmail.com

Mirpur, Dhaka

☆ https://github.com/Kallolx

@ www.linkedin.com/in/kamrul-hasan-dev

SUMMARY

I am a highly reliable, experienced Full Stack Web Developer with almost 3 years of experience in JavaScript Web Development using popular frameworks. I have an excellent understanding of modern web technologies; this positions me as an authority who can deliver high-performance applications that may be scaled infinitely by servers worldwide. I also follow through on projects with a keen interest in detail coupled with valuable communication skills which facilitate smooth-flowing teamwork and meeting project deliverables on time. On top of that, I can create user-friendly interactive experiences that are both simple yet compelling thus covering both front and back-end aspects.

EXPERIENCE

Freelancer

Upwork

2023 - Present

Managed JavaScript development and custom application creation

- Experts in programming with <u>JavaScript Framework</u> to build hand-crafted web applications to fit your unique business requirements.
- Optimizing web applications for speed and performance, ensuring a seamless user experience, and improving site performance by up to 30%.
- Collaborated with a team of developers, contributing to a 20% increase in team productivity

Custom Website Developer

Solo Developer

苗 2024 - Present 👂 Mirpur-12, Dhaka

Performed WordPress development and custom theme creation

- Worked on multiple projects per week, all of which were delivered on time
- Used WordPress, Elementor, and other plugins to build and edit custom themes, contributing to a 20% increase in website performance
- Collaborated with a team of developers, contributing to a 15% increase in team productivity

Web Development Spree

Personal Creations

苗 2021 - Present 👂 San Diego, CA

Gained practical experience in back-end development

- Developed and maintained code for 10 client websites primarily using HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Collaborated with a team of 2 developers, gaining valuable teamwork experience
- Worked on API integration and developed functionality for systems using

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Bangladesh University of Business and Technology

Mirpur, Dhaka

Higher Secondary School Certificate

Ghatail Cantonment Public School & College

🛱 2019 - 2021 👂 Ghatail, Tangail

SKILLS

Web Development			HTML		CSS	_
РНР	SQL	React		Javascript		_
Typescript		Next.	JS	Vite	e.JS	Git
MongoDB		WordPress Development				
Elementor		WordPress Plugins				

STRENGTHS

*/3	JavaScript Development Expert in custom website building
Q	Web Technologies Proficient in basic web technologies
	Communication Skills Known for excellent communication

MY OPEN-SOURCE WORK

Apple Website Clone (3D)

An immersive Apple clone website built with Next.js for seamless performance, styled with Tailwind CSS for a sleek and modern design and integrated with a headless CMS for easy content management. Features include dynamic routing, responsive layouts, and high-fidelity UI components, delivering an authentic Apple-like user experience.

https://github.com/Kallolx/apple_clone

Bubt Annex

A comprehensive Student Management Software developed with Angular for robust performance and scalability, Firebase for real-time data synchronization, and Material-UI for an intuitive and sleek design. The software includes features such as student enrollment, attendance tracking, grade management, and parent-teacher communication. providing an all-in-one solution for effective student administration and engagement.

https://github.com/Kallolx/StudentManagementSys tem